Guide to the Social Science Libraries and Information Services, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Social Science Libraries and Information Services, Yale University, records
1961-2005
RU 1025
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.25
(6 boxes)
The records consist annual reports and statistics of the Social Science Library from 1969-1997 as well as correspondence, memoranda, reports, proposals, and committee files of Sandra K. Peterson, Director of the Social Science Libraries and Information Services. The records document the various libraries and collections of the Social Science Libraries and Information Services, including the Social Science Library, Seeley G. Mudd Library, Statistics Library, Government Documents and Information Center, and Economic Growth Center Collection.
Yale University. Social Science Libraries and Information Services
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and department libraries and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Social Science Libraries and Information Services, 2007 and 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The records consist annual reports and statistics of the Social Science Library from 1969-1997 as well as correspondence, memoranda, reports, proposals, and committee files of Sandra K. Peterson, Director of the Social Science Libraries and Information Services. The records document the various libraries and collections of the Social Science Libraries and Information Services, including the Social Science Library, Seeley G. Mudd Library, Statistics Library, Government Documents and Information Center, and Economic Growth Center Collection.
Academic libraries -- Administration; Academic libraries -- Departmental libraries; Social science libraries; Yale University. Library; Yale University. Social Science Data Archive; Yale University. Social Science Libraries and Information Services
- Records of Sandra K. Peterson as Director of the Social Science Libraries, Yale University, 1961-2005; Accession 2007-A-122
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 2041
  - Administrative records of the Social Science Library
    - Library/Faculty Technology Grant, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Social Science Data Archive (SSDA)-History and Development, 1969-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Social Science Library Advisory Committee, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - News, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Social Science Library--History and Development, 1971-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Social Science Library-Collection Development, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Teacher Preparation Program, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Human Area Relations Files, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Social Science Library-Document Delivery Service, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Selected new acquisitions at SSL, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Seeley G. Mudd Library Space, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Administration & Organization, 1973-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Space Issues, 1977-88 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Equipment Needs, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Budgets & financial support, 1974-1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Staffing, 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Users, 1982-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Grant proposal, background information, budget, final report-- Forum on Geographic Information systems and the Impact for Libraries, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Biological, Social, Industrial and Cultural History of the Chicken through Print, Image, and Word
    - Exhibit tags, publicity materials, correspondence related to "chicken" exhibit, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committee Records of Sandra Peterson
    - Map Resources Group: Reports and documentation, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Public Printing Task Force: Reports, background information, vendor proposals, meeting records, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Reference Services Group: Grant proposal, final report, background information, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Science Park Patent Depository Library Committee: Reports, minutes, publications, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Serials Management Task Force: Reports, statistics, procedures, policies, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Service Quality Improvement Council: Charge, documentation of issues (Problem patron) (most info on web site), 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Economic Growth Center Collection
    - History and Development, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Recon Proposal, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Research Consortium, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Irving Fisher Collection, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Economic Growth Center Digital Library
    - Proposal, 9/6/2002-3/12/2003 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Copyright, 3/14/2005-3/15/2005 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Interim Report, 1/30/2004-2/26/2004 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Final report, 4/28/2005 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Document Solutions Invoices, 9/30/2003-10/31/2003 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Invoice and shipping information, 9/5-9/20/2003 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Other shipping information, 10/23/2003-1/5/2004 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Inventory of Mexican State Statistical vol., 9/30/2002-4/21/2004 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Document Solutions, Inc., 8/28/2003-9/3/2003 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Nesstar Limited, 11/30/2003-2/1/2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Web site, 6/6/2003-2.8/2005 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Presentations, 4/26/2004-8/3/2004 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - External Review, 7/2/2004-7/12/2004 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Timelines & Meeting Notes, 10/21/2003-12/15/2004 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Document Solutions-Pilot Test, 6/2001 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - APEX ePublishing, 4/30/2003-7/28/2003 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - APEX Publishing Pilot, 8/5/2003 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Byte Managers, 4/30/2003-7/25/2003 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Datamatics/Saztec, 4/30/2003-7/2/2003 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Digital Divide Data, 4/30/2003-7/18/2003 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Electronic Scriptorium, 4/30/2003-6/19/2003 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - iArchives, 4/30/2003-6/6/2003 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Lason, 4/30/2003-7/7/2003 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Northern Micrographics, 4/30/2003-7/7/2003 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - OCLC Preservation Service, 5/2/2003-6/3/2003 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - OutHub/Power Com Tech-Pilot (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Power Com Technologies, 5/2/2003-7/30/2003 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Queen's University-Belfast, 5/2/2003-8/7/2003 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - SPI Content Sciences, 5/2/2003-7/7/2003 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Yale-RIS, 8/21/2003-9/8/2003 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - 2ndVendor Proposals Rejected, 7/28/2003 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - 1022450, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Scanning, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - EGCDL2, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Nigeria Project, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Communications, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Notebooks, 202-2003 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Project DVDs, 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 68 - 74)
  - Government Documents & Information Center
    - Govt. Documents Advisory Group, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Govt. Doc. Advisory Group/Coll. Dev. Subcommittee, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence w/govt. officials about U.S. Federal depository program, 1983-2004 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Govt. Documents Web Pages, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - 130thanniversary GPO depository, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Selected New Acquisitions Newsletter, 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Guides and Brochures, 1985-2002 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Reclassification project, 1970-1996 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Electronic Bulletin Board Pilot Project, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - User Surveys, 1985,1992, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Canadian Electronic Publications Pilot Project, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Mass Deacidification Project, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - United Nations Scholars Workstation-User Surveys, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - United Nations Scholars' Workstation-history and development, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Govt. Information class for adm. & tech. Support staff, SCOPA grant proposal, documentation, final report, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 89)
- Annual reports and statistics, 1969-1997; Accession 2016-A-032
  In accordence with university policy, these records are restricted until January 1, 2032.
  - Annual reports
    - 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Statistics, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Statistical appendix, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)